Let's discuss the Talent Triangle and our
three domains.
So the Talent Triangle, we have,
if you look at the second slide,
technical project management, leadership,
and then strategic and
business management.
These are the three areas in which once
you get your PMP certification,
you will need to get 60 PD.
use professional development units in
these three areas, all right?
They tie directly into the new exam
domains, which you see in the red here.
Okay.
So our processes tie in with technical
project management, how we will integrate
the entire project, how will plan,
execute, execute, control, scope,
schedule, cost, quality,
risks, procurements,
communications,
stakeholder engagement, etc.
How we'll do our processes, how we'll take
a project from beginning to end.
We also see over here leadership.
This is all about the people,
stakeholders, including our team,
especially our team.
They're the ones who are going to be doing
the work of the project.
all right so we'll have to build a team
and power manage our team we'll have to
engage the stakeholders figure out who the
stakeholders are who's impacted by your
project out of them who's going to impact
us who's going to tell us what our
requirements are all right for example who
will need to communicate with who the
roles what roles will be on the project
it's etc.
All right.
And then the strategic and business
management ties into the third domain,
the business environment.
What is going on in the organization?
What are the strategic objectives?
Projects are a means for actually
obtaining objectives, strategic objectives.
So they have to align.
So we have to understand the business
environment.
And we as the PM, we'll have
to make sure that our project
aligns with the organization's
strategic objectives.
All right.
So all of these tie in together with how
you will continue to grow as a project
manager and how you will be assessed on
the exam.
All right.
Let's look at the next slide.
So the project manager's role within the
domains and project life cycles.
So we have predictive.
So life cycles are, I believe
we're already covered
or are, are covered in
detail in an upcoming lesson.
So remember the predictive is also called
waterfall or traditional
project management.
How projects normally happen, or at least
in the past.
So predictive is, again, where we will
define the scope early, early on.
We'll do a lot of planning early on,
and then we'll figure out what the cost
and the schedule with predictive life
cycles, usually the PM is in command and
in control of the project, all right,
making sure everything is being done,
telling the team members what need to be
done.
Whereas Agile is adaptive and iterative,
where we will be called a servant leader.
We wouldn't actually have the title of
project manager.
So we are a servant leader.
We will help and assist the team.
In Agile, the team members are empowered.
All right.
They will be deciding how to get the work
done on the projects.
All right.
So as a servant leader, we will assist the
team by looking through these bullets,
removing obstacles.
anything that can be impeding,
hindering progress of our team members,
making sure the team has the tools needed
to perform the work, and we will ensure
the team isn't interfered with during a
sprint.
So a sprint is a time boxed, usually two
to four weeks, where the team is working
on a specific amount of work within that
two to four week period.
So that's called a sprint or an iteration.
So we as a servant leader
will make sure none of
the stakeholders are going
up to our team members.
Oh, you do this little favor for me.
Can you do this or why are you doing that
or we shouldn't be doing that?
We will play interference making sure the
team isn't interfered
with during that sprint.
So they can focus on their work at the end
of that sprint is when we'll have a review
demo with the product
owner stakeholders to go over
what functionality was
created during that sprint.
Okay.
Then the product owner who represents the
customer can then say, oh, well,
we want these new requirements or based on
that demo.
that's not going to work we're going to
need something else so that then new
requirements will be added to the product
backlog okay so that's what agile means we
can adjust for the advantage of the
customer all right so in agile the entire
team is accountable for the project really
important there opposite of predictive or
maybe not opposite but
very far from predictive
where the PM is in control and empowered.
Agile, the team is empowered.
So keep that in mind.
All right.
If we look at the next
slide, the PM will often
facilitate meetings, primarily
the daily stand-up meeting.
So every single day on the Agile project,
the team members will discuss these three
bullets what did they work on yesterday
what are they going to do today and any
obstacles that they're facing now
obstacles will be will not be addressed
during the daily stand-up they'll be
listed like on a parking garage okay so
they'll just be listed they will be
handled, addressed in a separate meeting.
The daily stand-up is so
that each team member
knows and is discussing
what they did yesterday.
What are they going to do?
Do today?
Any problems are having.
Remember, the obstacles,
problems, impediments
will be discussed in a separate meeting.